MUKESH GADUPUDI

Data Scientist with 4+ years of experience in building multiprocessing python applications, overcoming complex architectural, and scalability issues. Proficient in statistical analysis, geospatial data science, machine learning, deep learning algorithms, and well-versed in languages, such as Python, Java, Go, SQL. Experience in startups and MNCs make me well suited to roles that require navigating uncertainty, but with high levels of autonomy.

% https://shanmu9898.github.io @ shanmu9898@icloud.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/MukeshGadupudi +65 87795427

nttps://github.com/shanmu9898 Singapore PR

EXPERIENCE

Senior Data Scientist

Zeus Living Pte.

🛗 Jan 2021 - Present

♥ Singapore

- Managed a 3-person Data team to develop Zeus' Geo Spatial ML-based Microservice. Increased booking conversion via recommender systems, provided competitive intelligence via geospatial modelling, and revamped on our dynamic pricing engine.
- Led the data team to develop Demand Zones, the product currently being used to pilot the expansion of Zeus to new places using GeoSpatial Data Science.
- Developed pricing algorithms and built end to end system to price Zeus listings using Search Demand, Occupancy and Price Elasticity which helped increase general occupancy by about 9%.
- Developed parallelised algorithms which sped up our systems >10X for various projects.
- Mentored interns to build systems such as Flex Lease Pricing, Similarity scoring model which sped new lead pricing by about 6 hours / lead on average.

Commodities Sales and Trading Tech Analyst

Goldman Sachs Pte.

Feb 2020 - Jan 2021

- Singapore
- Worked on the Front line to build trade booking systems, reconciliation systems using Java and a proprietary language called Slang.
- Secondary responsibility as a trading desk support covering a range of daily tasks, including PNL report generation, risk server maintenance, trade propagation, and system maintenance.
- Worked closely with traders, clients, valuations, and operations to ensure the accurate and timely booking of trades in various booking entities.

Software Engineering Intern

VISA

May 2019 - Aug 2019

- Singapore
- Built internal notification and patching microservices using Go.
- Developed the basic architecture to enable an active-active scenario with around 99.9% up time and resilience to handle any catastrophic events or failure for the microservices while extensively using tools like Swagger and Jenkins and following a TDD plan.

Algorithm Developer and Data Science Contractor Qsee.io

▼ Tel Aviv, Israel

- Applied various ML algorithms to analyze and find trends in Quality for products from various MNCs like Stanley and AlHadera showing they can reduce their revenue spent on quality checks by over 15% using libraries like Pandas
- Created a real-time web-based application with Flask and Django and integrated it with other services including Predictive Algorithms and Front End Analysis DashBoard.

SKILLS

General Skills

Machine Learning, Deep Learning, GeoSpatial DataScience, Data Visualisation

Technical Skills

Languages: Python, Java, Go, SQL Libraries: Scikit-Learn, Pandas, Numpy, TensorFlow, Pytorch

EDUCATION / COURSES

BComp in Computer Science National University of Singapore

₩ Jul 2016 - Dec 2019

• Highest Distinction in Machine Learning and AI

NOC Israel, Batch 15 **NUS Overseas Colleges**

Jul 2018 - Dec 2018

- Start Up Internship Program
- Technopreneurship

HONORS & AWARDS

- National Talent Search Scholar
- Winner of BizPrediction Contest
- Advanced Level Winner @Orbital
- Runner Up at #Boscheville2018

PROJECTS

Tetris Solver

- Genetic Algorithms, Noise Cross Entropy, Python
 - Created a self learning Python multiprocessing Tetris Game from scratch which could clear on average over a million rows using Genetic algorithms, Noisy Cross Entropy.

CNF-SAT-Solver

- Al Heuristics, Java
 - Built a Conjugative Normal Form (CNF) SAT Solver which can take CNF formulas with upto 140 variables and solve the equation using AI based heuristics.

Finding Waldo

- CV Algorithms, Python
 - Implemented CV algorithms from scratch to find Waldo from images without using deep learning of any sort.